

Having 4+ years of experience on power Bi and SQL server and having a good knowledge on building reports and dashboards and client requirement gathering and in time delivery.



Current Designation: Software Engineer Total Experience: 4 Year(s) 5 Month(s)

Current Company: Infosys Notice Period: Currently Serving Notice Period

Current Location: Hyderabad / Secunderabad Highest Degree: MS/M.Sc(Science) [Computers]

Pref. Location: Ahmedabad, Chennai, Bengaluru / Bangalore Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Software Engineer, Software Developer, Software Engineering, Software Development, Application Support, Project Management, Change Management, Defect Management, Quality Management, Requirement

Gathering, Desktop Support, Technical Support, Power Bi, SQL Server

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 21-Jan-21

Summary

Having 4+ years of experience in IT Professional career in Power BI, SQL Server 2008/2012.

Created many Power Bi, matrix Reports using the report designer.

Expert knowledge in creating Drill through reports, Drill down reports, Parameterized and Cascading reports.

Proficient knowledge in providing Security to the reports and deploying Projects.

Delivered advanced/complex reporting solutions such as Dashboards and Standardized reports using Power BI Desktop Created Dashboards with different style using Power BI components like Pie charts, Bar charts, Line, KPI Visuals, Custom visuals, etc.

Good knowledge of various DAX functions of Power BI technology.

Published reports into Power BI publisher and schedule the data sets, providing row level security.

Shared dashboards to users through Office 365, Content Packs.

Experience in writing simple/complex queries, T-SQL, Views, Stored Procedures, Functions, etc.

Work Experience

Infosys as Software Engineer

Apr 2016 to Till Date

Project: Eden AO Client: Ops Monitoring

Role: Power BI Developer (May 2018 to Till Date)

Responsibilities:-

Working on MS SQL Server and written queries to pull the data.

Experience on Importing Power Bi files to service, connecting to the data from MS SQL.

Working with gateways and scheduling the refresh and Creating reports and dashboards.

Good on Sharing the dashboards & providing the security, Embedding the Power Bi reports and Exporting /analyzing the data to excel.

Creating a drill down and drill through reports.

Have good Experience to Implement RLS as part of security.

Worked on Daily Notification reports for current status for all projects in company.

Have attended the client calls to understand and analyze the requirements.

As per the client requirements, rendering the Reports in the form PDF, Power Point.

Project 2

Client: PAREXEL (Subsidiary of Infosys)

Role: Power Bi Developer, SQL Server(May 2016 to May 2018)

Description:-

PAREXEL International is a global provider of biopharmaceutical services. It conducts clinical trials on behalf of its pharmaceutical clients to expedite the drug approval process.

Responsibilities:

Interacted with end-users to collect requirements and acquire the necessary domain knowledge to become a subject matter expert.

Understanding source systems and customer requirements.

Worked with Dashboards style of reports using all the Power BI components.

Worked with Pages and Page Visualizations in Power Bi Desktop.

Created Dashboards style of reports using Power Bi Desktop Visualizations like Bar Chart, Line Chart, Area Chart and Slicer etc.

Created the reports using charts like Pie, Bar, Line, KPI Visuals, Custom visuals, etc.

Charts are used in making reports more user-friendly in analysis purposes.

Developed User interactive Reports as business needs.

Published reports into Power BI publisher and schedule the data sets.

Shared dashboards to users through Office 365, Content Packs.

Developed complex SQL queries and create stored procedures to fetch data for reporting and to accomplish several computations.

Education

UG: B.Sc (Computers) from Sri Venkateshwara University (SVU), Tirupati in 2011

PG: MS/M.Sc(Science) (Computers) from Gate Institute of technology and management sciences, Tirupati in 2013

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
Power Bi,SQL SERVER			4 Year(s) 7 Month(s)

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Proficient			
Hindi	Proficient			
Tamil	Beginner			
Telugu	Proficient			

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Physically Challenged: No

Job Type: Permanent / Temporary

Employment Status: Full time